Local 1199 President Leon Davis Records 5206-PR
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- NY Urban Coalition, 1969-1971 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  Contains correspondence with the New York Urban Coalition regarding Yeshiva Teachers Strike, meetings, scholarship programs, unemployment, luncheons, government campaigns, housing projects, the Adult Career Ladder Program, and Davis' reelection on to the board of directors. Also contains meeting minutes from NY Urban Coalition board of directors meeting, and a policy statement regarding low-wage workers in New York City.
- Personnel Applications, 1968-1969 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  Contains correspondence between Davis and job applicants for various 1199 positions including office manager. Also contains resumes, and job advertisements for the New York Times.
- Personnel Applications, 1964-1965 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  Contains correspondence with people seeking employment at 1199, in particular students who seek summer employment. Also contains resumes.
- Personnel Requests, 1970-1971 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  Contains correspondence with people seeking employment at 1199. Also contains resumes.
- Political Action, 1970-1971 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  Contains correspondence, statements, and memorandums regarding various political situations including elections, court cases, laws, etc.
- Political Action, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  Contains telegrams and correspondence with civil rights groups regarding race relations, and housing in New York City. Also contains correspondence regarding court cases.
- Public Housing, 1966-1968 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  Contains housing project proposal, various brochures and reports about housing construction plans. Also contains correspondence about housing project plans, and list of people involved in the project.
- Reports-Membership [folder 1 of 2], 1968 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  Contains detailed 1199 membership reports for each month in 1968.
- Reports-Membership [folder 2 of 2], 1968 (Box 22, Folder 8)
- Reports-Membership [folder 1 of 2], 1969 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  Contains detailed 1199 membership reports for most months in 1969.
- Reports-Membership [folder 2 of 2], 1969 (Box 23, Folder 2)
- Reports, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  Contains various 1199 reports from 1970 including a yearly report of membership meeting attendance, grievance reports, annual reports, and membership reports. Also contains handwritten notes, financial statements and a memorandum.
- Reports, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  Contains memorandums and correspondence regarding the compilation of the annual report. Also contains a list of monthly reports, financial reports, and handwritten notes.
- Monthly Reports, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  Contains monthly membership reports, and hospital division activities reports.
- Monthly Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  Contains monthly hospital division activities reports and contract information reports from January to June.
- Monthly Reports, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  Contains monthly hospital division activities reports and contract information reports from June to December.
- Finance Reports, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  Contains 1199 statistical reports for each month in 1972.
- Annual Report, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  Contains the annual report, the strike and defense fund financial report, a report to the delegates assembly, and various handwritten notes and financial statements and statistics.
- Monthly Reports [folder 1 of 2], 1972 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  Contains 1199 Division Activities Reports for January through June 1972.
- Monthly Reports [folder 2 of 2], 1972 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  Contains 1199 Division Activities Reports for July through December 1972.
- RWDSU, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  Contains correspondence between Davis and the Retail, Wholesale, and Department Store Union (RWDSU) regarding pension plans.
- RWDSU Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  Contains correspondence between Davis and the RWDSU regarding meetings, strikes, current events, and conventions. Also contains telegrams, handwritten notes, invitations and invoices.
- RWDSU Correspondence, 1969 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  Contains correspondence with RWDSU regarding union policies, laws, meetings, and the charges against executive board member David Livingston.
- RWDSU Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  Contains correspondence with RWDSU regarding Livingston charges, 1199 membership, meetings, the AFL-CIO, current events, and pension plans. Also contains a meeting agenda, a proposal, resolutions, an agreement, a statement of assets and liabilities, and telegrams.
- RWDSU Correspondence, 1972 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  Contains correspondence with RWSDU regarding meetings, and pension issues. Also contains national union membership reports for July through September.
- RWDSU Convention Proceedings, 1956-1960 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  Contains correspondence with RWDSU regarding meetings and current issues. Also contains RWDSU meeting minutes, resolutions, president's reports, financial reports, and financial statements.
- RWDSU Convention Proceedings, 1960-1967 (Box 26, Folder 1)
- RWDSU Pension Plans, 1965-1969 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  Contains RWDSU pension plan summary, highlights of the pension plan, statement of assets and liabilities, budget estimates, eligible retirees, proposed amendments to the plan, and staff retirement plan booklet.
- RWDSU Minutes, 1950-1969 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  Contains RWDSU meeting minutes from 1967 through 1969. Also contains Proceedings of the Distributive Workers Union Founding Convention from 1950.
- RWDSU Convention Proceedings, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  Contains copy of an 1199 News article on the RWDSU. Also contains resolutions, and correspondence and brochures regarding RWDSU Convention.
- Review of Union Activities, 1967-1968 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  Contains reviews of 1199 union meetings, each 1199 division, and the 1199 benefit plan.
- Roosevelt Hospital, 1970-1971 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  Contains correspondence between lawyers, 1199, and Roosevelt Hospital regarding the collective bargaining agreement and an arbitration case between 1199 and Roosevelt Hospital. Also contains court proceedings of the arbitration case and the decision of the mediators.
- Roosevelt Hospital, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  Contains correspondence between Davis and the hospital regarding an arbitration case. Also contains NLRB decision on the arbitration case.
- Rules and Regulations, 1959-1969 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  Contains staff wage and employment policy, memorandum of agreement between 1199 and office employees union regarding benefits plan, clarification of rules and regulations, salary schedules and actual agreement between 1199 and the office employees union.
- Russian Visit, 1967 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  Contains correspondence, written notes, an agenda, and receipts regarding Davis' trip to the Soviet Union. Also contains an envelope with pictures from his trip.
- Salute to Israel, 1957-1960 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  Contains correspondence, invitations, and flyers regarding the Salute to Israel hosted by 1199.
- Salute to Israel, 1960-1966 (Box 27, Folder 5)
- School Decentralization, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  Contains a plan for development of New York City school districts, a statement from a school board, and revisions to the decentralization plan.
- Senate Subcommittee, 1965 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  Contains a court summons for 1199 to appear before the Senate.
- Sipser, Weinstock, Weinmann, and Eisner, 1969-1971 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  Contains correspondence with lawyers regarding legal fees and expenses and arbitration cases.
- Special Union Meetings, 1967-1969 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  Contains form letters inviting 1199 members to various special 1199 delegate meetings.
- Staff Development Program, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  Contains correspondence between Davis and the Cornell University ILR school regarding a delegate training program for 1199 delegates.
- Staff Development Program, 1970-1971 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  Contains correspondence between Davis and the Cornell University ILR school regarding a delegate training program for 1199 delegates, and regarding Cornell students visiting 1199 and talking with organizers.
- State Department of Health, 1970-1971 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  Contains correspondence with lawyers and the State Department of Health regarding the financial reports of hospitals.
- Taft Hartley Act, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  Contains a complete analysis of the new Taft Hartley Act as well as a booklet of questions about the act, political cartoons about the act, and a summary of the act.
- Trade Union Division of SANE, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  Contains a ledger of cash receipts, cash disbursements, and the general ledger of the Trade Union Division of SANE.
- Trip to the Soviet Union, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  Contains correspondence with various government, hospital and union official in the Soviet Union discussing Davis' upcoming trip. Also contains an agenda, receipts, pictures, and travel arrangements for his trip to the Soviet Union.
- Union Hospital Management Conferences, 1967 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  Contains correspondence with hospitals regarding a conference for hospitals and 1199 to get together and discuss issues. Also contains list of people who attended the conference.
- Wage and Price Freeze, 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  Contains documents summarizing president Nixon's 90 day wage and price freeze. Also contains correspondence with government officials and the AFL-CIO regarding the wage freeze.
- Miscellaneous, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  Contains a copy of the Industrial Union Department of the AFL-CIO's IUD Digest that contains an article written by Davis. Also contains an 1199 organizing flyer.